# Eleazar Hernandez

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineer/tech lead with 2 years of freelance experience in web applications in the retail and legal space, leading, designing, writing, and testing web applications for small businesses to scale their maximum outreach and business output. Coming from education, I have led and supported teams in school/district wide events, as well as reviewed, troubleshooted, and documented company projects and processes for internal use.

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Location: Dallas-Fort Worth, TX Email: eleazarfhernandez@gmail.com

Phone: (281) 871-1100

LinkedIn: Click here Github: Click here

## **SKILLS**

✓ TypeScript/JavaScript ✓ React ✓ Node.is **✓** Git ✓ Communication Skills ✓ Next.js ✓ Java ✓ Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) **✓** AWS ✓ Vercel ✓ Firebase ✓ Tailwind CSS ✓ Azure ✓ Agile ✓ Python ✓ PostgreSOL ✓ SOL

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ROTATE TRANSLATION

Software Engineer - Full Stack, Technical Support

Remote

LIVE SITE (PREVIEW): HTTPS://PAYMENT-FORM-ROTATE-TRANSLATION.VERCEL.APP

01/2024-PRESENT

Source Code: https://github.com/ehernandez42/payment-form-rotate-translation

ROTATE TRANSLATION IS A SERVICE SPECIALIZING IN TRANSLATING FULL FLEDGED LEGAL DOCUMENTS FROM LEGAL PROFESSIONALS ADEPT IN CONTRACTS, MOTIONS, AND OTHER FORMS OF LEGAL WRITINGS.

- Designing, planning, executing, and testing a Full Stack web application for clients to distribute information and process payment with scalability and efficiency in mind, resulting in a product that can handle up to 100 million users and 10 millions API calls per day.
- Tech Stack Vercel (CI/CD capabilities); React, CSS, and TypeScript for Front-Endt, Stripe API (Application Programming Interface), NoSQL(Firebase) database for storing user information.
- Provided technical support through extensive design, addressing business needs and translating into software user stories to create a secure and efficient user experience, resulting in 40% more efficiency and 100% modular-monolithic code structure.

# NEXTGEN IT STAFFING

Remote 09/2023-03/2024

**Software Engineer - Intern** Nextgen IT is staffing and recruiting firm for IT professionals worldwide. I specifically worked on a project involved in the

SkillBridge program. Wrote backend code for an open-source internal learning management system using Node.js and Netlify for over 100 internal, resulting in employees accessing 6 different proprietary courses to help internal teams learn and

- progress through their employee training. Provided technical support and collaborated extensively with teams from all over the United States and India to
- discuss issues and debug software, gathering and analyzing information and document requirements for the execution of the system in comparison to the courses market (Coursera, Udemy), resulting in a final internal tool.
- Maintaining assigned relational databases on employees, updating data as employees progressed through the course, resulting in 100% progress check for individuals going through the program.

#### TRIPTYCH COFFEE CO

Remote

08/2023-09/2023

Lead Front-End Software Developer, Technical Support Representative LIVE SITE: HTTPS://TRIPTYCHCOFFEECO.COM/

Triptych Coffee Co. is a specialty coffee business specializing in mobile coffee experiences.

Developed front-end site using Squarespace Content Management System and HTML/CSS, resulting in the company's official online presence and point of contact.

- Developed an automated emailing service based on business needs delivering client bookings to the inbox of the booking agents using DNS services, resulting in 30% increase in web traffic and business.
- Analyzed and troubleshooted technical issues, helping the team to deploy changes 25% faster causing less
  downtime for the client to use their site.

ALDINE ISD Houston, TX
Elementary Music Teacher Nov 2021-June 2024

Aldine ISD is a public-school district in North Houston, TX.

- Create engaging lessons for learners on a weekly basis, resulting in 75% student retention and 50% increased effectiveness in school performances and showcases
- Led teams on several school-wide projects including a 100% participation in events involving different holidays and important days.
- Collaborated with and provided technical support for departments, identifying opportunities for school-wide operational improvement, resulting in 30% increased efficiency in regulating and managing learners in music presentations and 80% overall parent satisfaction rate of musical presentations from a technological standpoint.

## **EDUCATION**

#### WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY

Remote

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

2022 - 2024

- Fully remote, self-paced program
- Certification in Linux

#### TEXAS WOMAN'S UNIVERSITY

Denton, TX

Masters Degree in Music, Education

2018 - 2021

- Masters Thesis: Survey in Music Technology in middle school classrooms, 2020-2021 year
- Teaching Assistant in Music Technology course

## UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS

Denton, TX 2013 - 2017

Bachelor's Degree in Integrative Studies

- Studies in music and communicative studies
- Leadership positions resident assistant

## **PROJECTS**

HTML/CSS Generator May 2024

Github Link

- With this tool, you will be able to get html elements with css onto your code editor. Think of it as a shortcut for some of the elements that a developer may use when working on a project.
- (See screenshots or README when you click on the link)

# SUPPLEMENTAL WORK

# JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Lite virtual experience program on Forage

March 2024

- Completed a simulation focused on the process of completing an engineering ticket for a system in the credit-card rewards department of JPMorgan Chase & Co.
- Created a new class to get an existing system up and running
- Wrote a test suite for the class added

# **CodePath Fellow - Intermediate Technical Interview Prep(TIP)**

June 2024 - Present

 Selected to participate and work with a cohort of other Computer Science students on Data Structures, Algorithms, and career prep

#### Associate Director, Aldine ISD Orff Ensemble

August 2022 - May 2023

• Directed and managed a highly-selected group of students to represent the school district in city-wide competitions and performances, resulting in performance honors and awards from several acclaimed Houston elementary school adjudicators.